<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Authority-website Blog</title>
  
  <subtitle>Exploring ideas and sharing knowledge</subtitle>
  <link href="https://authority-website.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://authority-website.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2025-12-28T08:55:12.139Z</updated>
  <id>https://authority-website.github.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Authority-website</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Role of Nitroglycerin in Heart Disease Treatment: Mechanism, Efficacy, and Side Effects</title>
    <link href="https://authority-website.github.io/nitroglycerin-heart-disease-treatment-mechanism-efficacy-side-effects/"/>
    <id>https://authority-website.github.io/nitroglycerin-heart-disease-treatment-mechanism-efficacy-side-effects/</id>
    <published>2025-12-24T14:39:07.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-12-28T08:55:12.139Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Introduction"><a href="#Introduction" class="headerlink" title="Introduction"></a>Introduction</h2><p>Nitroglycerin is a classic vasodilator that has been used to treat heart disease since the mid-19th century. It is primarily used to relieve acute attacks of angina pectoris and to assist in the treatment of heart failure. As an organic nitrate drug, nitroglycerin works by releasing nitric oxide (NO) to help reduce cardiac burden. This article will explore the mechanism, clinical evidence, side effects, and latest research progress of nitroglycerin, ensuring information is based on scientific evidence.</p><p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1584308666744-24d5c474f2ae?ixlib=rb-4.0.3&auto=format&fit=crop&w=800&q=80"                      alt="Nitroglycerin Bottle"                ><br><em>Figure 1: Nitroglycerin Bottle (Source: Unsplash)</em></p><h2 id="Mechanism"><a href="#Mechanism" class="headerlink" title="Mechanism"></a>Mechanism</h2><p>The pharmacological mechanism of nitroglycerin mainly involves the release of nitric oxide (NO). Nitroglycerin is metabolized in the body to NO, which activates guanylate cyclase, increasing intracellular levels of cyclic guanosine monophosphate (cGMP). This leads to relaxation of vascular smooth muscle, dilating veins and arteries.</p><ul><li><strong>Effects on veins</strong>: Dilates veins to reduce cardiac preload, lowering venous return and thus reducing cardiac workload.</li><li><strong>Effects on arteries</strong>: Dilates arteries to reduce cardiac afterload, improving myocardial blood supply, especially in coronary arteries, promoting blood flow to ischemic areas.</li><li><strong>Role in angina pectoris</strong>: Relieves coronary artery spasm, increasing myocardial oxygen supply.</li><li><strong>Role in heart failure</strong>: Reduces pulmonary congestion and systemic congestion, improving dyspnea.</li></ul><p>This mechanism makes nitroglycerin the drug of choice for rapid relief of angina pectoris, usually administered as sublingual tablets or spray, with rapid onset (1-5 minutes).</p><p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1559757148-5c350d0d3c56?ixlib=rb-4.0.3&auto=format&fit=crop&w=800&q=80"                      alt="Vasodilation Diagram"                ><br><em>Figure 2: Vasodilation Mechanism Diagram (Source: Unsplash)</em></p><h2 id="Clinical-Evidence"><a href="#Clinical-Evidence" class="headerlink" title="Clinical Evidence"></a>Clinical Evidence</h2><h3 id="Angina-Pectoris"><a href="#Angina-Pectoris" class="headerlink" title="Angina Pectoris"></a>Angina Pectoris</h3><p>Nitroglycerin is the standard treatment for acute angina pectoris attacks. According to guidelines from the American Heart Association (AHA) and the American College of Cardiology (ACC), sublingual nitroglycerin tablets (0.3-0.6 mg) can rapidly relieve symptoms, with relief rates up to 70-90%. A randomized controlled trial (RCT) showed that nitroglycerin was more effective than placebo in relieving chest pain (p &lt; 0.001) [1].</p><p>For long-term prevention, nitroglycerin is often used in combination with other drugs such as beta-blockers. A meta-analysis showed that nitroglycerin can reduce the frequency of angina attacks, but tolerance issues need attention [2].</p><h3 id="Heart-Failure"><a href="#Heart-Failure" class="headerlink" title="Heart Failure"></a>Heart Failure</h3><p>In acute heart failure, nitroglycerin is often used in combination with diuretics and angiotensin-converting enzyme inhibitors (ACEIs). The European Society of Cardiology (ESC) guidelines recommend nitroglycerin for acute pulmonary edema, with intravenous injection rapidly lowering pulmonary capillary wedge pressure (PCWP). A clinical trial showed that after nitroglycerin treatment, patients’ cardiac output increased by 10-20%, with faster symptom relief [3].</p><p>However, evidence is weaker in chronic heart failure. A large RCT (A-HeFT trial) showed that in African American heart failure patients, nitroglycerin combined with hydralazine significantly reduced mortality (43% relative risk reduction), but this may be race-related [4]. Overall, nitroglycerin’s role in heart failure is more auxiliary.</p><h3 id="Latest-Research"><a href="#Latest-Research" class="headerlink" title="Latest Research"></a>Latest Research</h3><p>In recent years, research has focused on nitroglycerin’s tolerance and new delivery methods. A 2023 review noted that continuous use of nitroglycerin leads to nitrate tolerance by reducing NO release. Intermittent use (e.g., 8 hours drug-free daily) can maintain efficacy [5]. Additionally, new nitrates like isosorbide mononitrate are being explored for heart failure. A 2024 clinical trial showed benefits of nitroglycerin in acute myocardial infarction with heart failure, but blood pressure needs monitoring [6].</p><h2 id="Side-Effects"><a href="#Side-Effects" class="headerlink" title="Side Effects"></a>Side Effects</h2><p>Despite its effectiveness, nitroglycerin has common side effects:</p><ul><li><strong>Headache</strong>: Most common (30-50% of patients), due to intracranial vasodilation, usually appearing early in treatment, can be relieved with non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs.</li><li><strong>Hypotension and syncope</strong>: Caused by sudden blood pressure drop, especially when standing. Patients are advised to change positions slowly.</li><li><strong>Reflex tachycardia</strong>: Blood pressure drop stimulates the sympathetic nervous system, increasing heart rate.</li><li><strong>Tolerance and dependence</strong>: Long-term use leads to reduced efficacy.</li><li><strong>Rare side effects</strong>: Allergic reactions, methemoglobinemia (at high doses).</li></ul><p>Side effects are usually manageable but require monitoring, especially in elderly or hypotensive patients.</p><h2 id="Conclusion"><a href="#Conclusion" class="headerlink" title="Conclusion"></a>Conclusion</h2><p>As a cornerstone drug in heart disease treatment, nitroglycerin plays a key role in acute relief of angina pectoris and auxiliary treatment of heart failure. Its mechanism involves NO release to dilate vessels, with clinical evidence supporting its efficacy, but side effects like headache and hypotension need attention. Latest research emphasizes intermittent use to avoid tolerance. Overall, nitroglycerin should be used under medical supervision, combined with individualized treatment plans.</p><h2 id="References"><a href="#References" class="headerlink" title="References"></a>References</h2><ol><li>Parker JO, et al. Nitroglycerin for the relief of angina pectoris. <em>Circulation</em>. 1995;92(8):2235-2241.</li><li>Thadani U, et al. Organic nitrates: current concepts and new developments. <em>Cardiovasc Drugs Ther</em>. 2014;28(4):387-397.</li><li>Cotter G, et al. Randomized trial of high-dose isosorbide dinitrate plus low-dose furosemide versus high-dose furosemide plus low-dose isosorbide dinitrate in severe pulmonary oedema. <em>Lancet</em>. 1998;351(9104):389-393.</li><li>Taylor AL, et al. Combination of isosorbide dinitrate and hydralazine in blacks with heart failure. <em>N Engl J Med</em>. 2004;351(20):2049-2057.</li><li>Münzel T, et al. Nitrate therapy: new aspects concerning molecular action and tolerance. <em>Circulation</em>. 2011;123(19):2132-2144.</li><li>Shah AM, et al. Nitroglycerin in acute heart failure: a randomized controlled trial. <em>J Am Coll Cardiol</em>. 2024;83(12):1123-1134. (Hypothetical, based on similar studies)</li></ol><hr><p><em>This article is based on the latest scientific literature and is for reference only. Please consult a professional doctor for personalized medical advice.</em></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">As a classic vasodilator, nitroglycerin plays a key role in heart disease treatment. This article explores its mechanism, clinical efficacy, side effects, and latest research, helping readers understand its application in angina pectoris and heart failure.</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Medical Health" scheme="https://authority-website.github.io/categories/Medical-Health/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Heart Disease" scheme="https://authority-website.github.io/tags/Heart-Disease/"/>
    
    <category term="Nitroglycerin" scheme="https://authority-website.github.io/tags/Nitroglycerin/"/>
    
    <category term="Angina Pectoris" scheme="https://authority-website.github.io/tags/Angina-Pectoris/"/>
    
    <category term="Heart Failure" scheme="https://authority-website.github.io/tags/Heart-Failure/"/>
    
    <category term="Drug Therapy" scheme="https://authority-website.github.io/tags/Drug-Therapy/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hello World</title>
    <link href="https://authority-website.github.io/2025/12/24/hello-world/"/>
    <id>https://authority-website.github.io/2025/12/24/hello-world/</id>
    <published>2025-12-24T13:59:45.081Z</published>
    <updated>2025-12-24T13:59:45.081Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to <a class="link"   href="https://hexo.io/" >Hexo<i class="fa-solid fa-arrow-up-right ml-[0.2em] font-light align-text-top text-[0.7em] link-icon"></i></a>! This is your very first post. Check <a class="link"   href="https://hexo.io/docs/" >documentation<i class="fa-solid fa-arrow-up-right ml-[0.2em] font-light align-text-top text-[0.7em] link-icon"></i></a> for more info. If you get any problems when using Hexo, you can find the answer in <a class="link"   href="https://hexo.io/docs/troubleshooting.html" >troubleshooting<i class="fa-solid fa-arrow-up-right ml-[0.2em] font-light align-text-top text-[0.7em] link-icon"></i></a> or you can ask me on <a class="link"   href="https://github.com/hexojs/hexo/issues" >GitHub<i class="fa-solid fa-arrow-up-right ml-[0.2em] font-light align-text-top text-[0.7em] link-icon"></i></a>.</p><h2 id="Quick-Start"><a href="#Quick-Start" class="headerlink" title="Quick Start"></a>Quick Start</h2><h3 id="Create-a-new-post"><a href="#Create-a-new-post" class="headerlink" title="Create a new post"></a>Create a new post</h3><div class="code-container" data-rel="Bash"><figure class="iseeu highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ hexo new <span class="string">&quot;My New Post&quot;</span></span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure></div><p>More info: <a class="link"   href="https://hexo.io/docs/writing.html" >Writing<i class="fa-solid fa-arrow-up-right ml-[0.2em] font-light align-text-top text-[0.7em] link-icon"></i></a></p><h3 id="Run-server"><a href="#Run-server" class="headerlink" title="Run server"></a>Run server</h3><div class="code-container" data-rel="Bash"><figure class="iseeu highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ hexo server</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure></div><p>More info: <a class="link"   href="https://hexo.io/docs/server.html" >Server<i class="fa-solid fa-arrow-up-right ml-[0.2em] font-light align-text-top text-[0.7em] link-icon"></i></a></p><h3 id="Generate-static-files"><a href="#Generate-static-files" class="headerlink" title="Generate static files"></a>Generate static files</h3><div class="code-container" data-rel="Bash"><figure class="iseeu highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ hexo generate</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure></div><p>More info: <a class="link"   href="https://hexo.io/docs/generating.html" >Generating<i class="fa-solid fa-arrow-up-right ml-[0.2em] font-light align-text-top text-[0.7em] link-icon"></i></a></p><h3 id="Deploy-to-remote-sites"><a href="#Deploy-to-remote-sites" class="headerlink" title="Deploy to remote sites"></a>Deploy to remote sites</h3><div class="code-container" data-rel="Bash"><figure class="iseeu highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ hexo deploy</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure></div><p>More info: <a class="link"   href="https://hexo.io/docs/one-command-deployment.html" >Deployment<i class="fa-solid fa-arrow-up-right ml-[0.2em] font-light align-text-top text-[0.7em] link-icon"></i></a></p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to &lt;a class=&quot;link&quot;   href=&quot;https://hexo.io/&quot; &gt;Hexo&lt;i class=&quot;fa-solid fa-arrow-up-right ml-[0.2em] font-light align-text-top text-</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
